（春野はるのサクラ）ん…
（チヨ）サクラ 恐れるな
Sakura, do not fear...
このわしがおる
お前は 後ろへ下がっておれ
I'm here. You step back.
操襲刃そうしゅうは
Assault Blade.
（サソリ）
俺にたてつこうってんなら
しかたねえ
If you're going to defy me,
then I guess I have no choice.
そこのガキと一緒に
俺のコレクションになるか
Will you join that kid
as additions to my collection,
Grandma Chiyo...?
チヨバアよ
（サクラ）あっ…
うっ なんなの？ あれ
Wh-What's that...?
あれはサソリの本体ではない
That's not Sasori's real body...
あれが本体じゃないっていうのは
なんとなく分かります
I can kind of tell
that's not his real body.
そう　あれは…
Yes...
That's...a puppet.
傀儡くぐつ人形じゃ
でも 本体はどこなんですか？
But where's his real body?
傀儡使いは
後ろで糸を操ってるはずでしょ
Puppet Masters are supposed to be
pulling the strings from behind, right?
His real body's inside that.
本体は あの中じゃ
あっ…
Inside?
中？
傀儡使いは 接近戦に弱い
Puppet Masters have trouble
with close-range combat.
After all, when controlling a puppet,
they are prone to openings ...
人形を操るとき
隙が生じやすいからのう
それを克服したのが
つまりは あの傀儡じゃ
That puppet there has basically
surmounted that problem.
傀儡が…
The puppet acts as a shield
as well as a weapon.
よろいとなり
そして それが武器にもなる
サソリのおはこ ヒルコじゃ
It's Sasori's specialty, Hiruko.
（サクラ）
チヨバア様 あの傀儡のことを？
Lady Chiyo... About that puppet...
うん
I know a lot about it.
わしも よく知っておる
（サソリ）俺のコレクションが
どうやって作られるか 知ってるか？
Do you know how I make
my collection?
まずは 臓物を引きずり出す
First. I pull out the organs...
Then after I've washed
the body nice and clean...
きれいに洗ったら 次は血抜きだ
I extract the blood.
うっ…
（サソリ）
腐らねえように処理したら
仕込みを組んで
Once I've prepared the body
so it won't decay,
I fill it with hidden weapons
and then...
傀儡コレクションの１丁上がりだ
it becomes a complete addition
to my puppet collection.
Just as the old woman said,
this form you see...
ババアの言うとおり 俺のこの姿
Hiruko, is a part of my collection.
ヒルコもコレクションの１体だ
そして そこの小娘とチヨは
And with the little girl and
Granny Chiyo added...
I'll have exactly three hundred
in my collection.
お前ら２人で ちょうど300体になる
俺の芸術だ
It's my art!
♪～
～♪
Hiruko vs. Two Kunoichi!
Gaara...!
（うずまきナルト）我愛羅があらは…
Is it okay for you to be taking me on?
（デイダラ）俺なんか
相手にしてていいのか？
うん？
写輪眼しゃりんがんのカカシ先生よ
Kakashi Sensei of the Sharingan.
言っちゃあなんだが
I hate to say this, but...
サソリの旦那は 俺より強いぜ
my man Sasori is stronger than I am...
Probably...
たぶんな うん
Our ideas of art are
quite different, though.
芸術に対する考えは
だいぶ違うがな
Art, huh?
芸術か
Lady Chiyo?
（サクラ）チヨバア様
砂隠すながくれにいたとき
Back when he was
in the Hidden Sand,
he was called a master craftsman...
あやつは 天才造形師と言われ
and he built many excellent puppets.
数多くのすぐれた傀儡を作った
だが それ以上に心血を注いだのが
But he devoted most of his energy
人を傀儡にして
コレクションすること
into turning people into puppets
and collecting them.
あっ…
それを芸術と称してな
He calls that "art."
And that puppet Hiruko...
あの傀儡ヒルコも
かつては よその里の忍じゃった
used to be a Shinobi
from another village.
それがサソリの手であのような姿に
He was turned into that form
you see there by Sasori...
人であったときの姿を
残したままの傀儡
He turned into a "human puppet"
while still maintaining
his original human form.
人傀儡となったのじゃ
A human puppet.
“人傀儡”
（サソリ）
お前らも すぐにそうなる
That's what'll happen to you
very soon.
You'll become one of
my works of art.
俺の芸術作品の１つにな
あっ
ヒルコは 攻防一体の傀儡
Hiruko is a puppet with
a great attack and defense.
Be that as it may, first we need
to extract Sasori out of Hiruko.
とにかくじゃ
まずは サソリを
ヒルコから引きずり出さねばならん
Then, how do we do that?
じゃあ どうすれば？
傀儡で最も恐ろしいのは 仕込みだ
The most frightening thing about
a puppet is their hidden weapon.
仕込みが分からねば
If we can't figure out what they are,
どこから どの手順で
攻撃がくるのか分からぬ
we won't be able to tell where
and how he'll attack.
But Lady Chiyo,
でも チヨバア様は
あの傀儡のカラクリをよく知ってる
you know a lot about the mechanisms
of that puppet...
We've got the edge.
こっちに 分ぶがありますね
（チヨ）うむ
Yes...
That's why I thought I could
take him on by myself at first.
じゃから最初は
わし１人でやれると踏んでおった
最初は？
At first?
じゃが そうもいかんようじゃ
But...it doesn't look like it'll work.
What do you mean?
どういうことです？
わしの知っている
かつての傀儡ヒルコとは
It has a different form than
the Hiruko puppet I used to know.
少し形態が変わっている
えっ
First of all, he didn't have
a shell like that on his back.
（チヨ）まず 背中に
あれほどの甲羅はなかった
He probably has a better ability
to guard now.
よりガードを強化したのじゃろう
And it's the first time
I've seen that left arm.
あの左手も初めて見る
となると いちばん重要な
仕込みカラクリも
In which case, his most important
hidden weapon mechanism
might also have been improved.
改造しておるかもしれん
What do we do?
どうすれば？
サソリを倒すには まず…
In order to defeat Sasori,
first we must destroy that Hiruko.
あのヒルコを ばらすしかない
However, I don't have that kind
of destructive power.
…が それだけの破壊力は
わしの手の内にない
しかしじゃ サクラ
But Sakura...
ん？
You do.
お前にはある
綱手つなで姫直伝の…
That incredible strength
Princess Tsunade...
personally taught you.
怪力がな
Okay!
（サクラ）はい！
タアー！
（チヨ）よく聞け サクラ
Listen carefully, Sakura.
まず ヤツに近づき
First, get close to him...
傀儡をたたき壊す
お前の怪力でな
and smash the puppet with
your incredible strength.
うん
However, you must dodge all
of his hidden device attacks.
ただし 仕込みカラクリの攻撃は
全てかわさなくてはならん
全てを完璧にじゃ
All of them, perfectly!
かすることすら許されん
You must not even get a scratch.
毒ですね
Poison, right...?
そうじゃ
That's right... Even a scratch
can turn into a fatal wound.
かすり傷さえ致命傷になる
（サクラ）いきます
Here I go.
（カンクロウ）
うわあ うわっ ああ…
（サクラ）しっかり押さえて
Hold him down!
（医療忍者たち）は… はい
Right!
攻撃をかわすには
In order to dodge his attacks,
you must figure out the tricks
to the hidden weapons of
the master craftsman's puppet.
造形師の
傀儡の仕込みの癖を知り
とっさの攻撃を
回避する状況判断能力がいる
And you must also be able
to immediately assess
how to dodge his attacks.
私には そのどちらも足らなすぎる
I don't think I can do either at all...
Indeed...
確かにな
それを得るには
多くの実戦経験が必要じゃからな
In order to do that,
a lot of actual battle experience
is required.
Then...how can I...?
それじゃ どうやって？
What do I look like to you?
お前には わしがどう見える？
ただの頼りないババアか？
Do I just look like
an unreliable old bag...?
あっ
それとも…
Or...
Leave it to me...
任せておけ
そのために わしがおる
That's why I'm here!
I have much more actual
battle experience than he does.
実戦経験は あやつの比ではない
And he knows that.
それが 分かっとるからこそ
That's why he doesn't attempt
to attack carelessly.
あやつ うかつに
手を出してこようとはせん
This man who so hates
waiting for people,
あれほど 人を待ったり
待たせたりするのが嫌いな男が
and being kept waiting by them...
And besides...
それにじゃ
I made the first move.
先手は打った
あっ…
Sakura. Lend me your ears.
サクラ 耳を貸せ
You and I...
わしと お前で
will defeat him!
あやつを倒す
（サソリ）ふんっ！
What're they planning?
何をたくらんでいる？
From here, I can't make out
what they're saying...
ここからは ぎりぎり聞き取れないか
あっ…
Understood.
分かりました
I'll give it a try.
やってみます
（サソリ）そろそろいいか？
Are you about ready?
知ってんだろ？
You know I hate to
be kept waiting, don't you?
俺は待たされんのが 嫌いだってよ
Rest easy. We'll...
安心しろ すぐ…
けりをつけてやる
...put an end to this soon.
（サソリ）んんっ
It looks like they've started.
（デイダラ）始まったようだな
（ナルト）あっ…
（はたけカカシ）なっ…
Is just that little girl...
and that old bag...
（デイダラ）
あんな小娘とババアだけで
サソリの旦那の相手が
務まるかな？ うん？
really up to the task of taking
on my man Sasori?
So he wants to fight Naruto
one-on-one if he can, huh?
（カカシ）できれば ナルトと差しで
やり合いたいというわけか
He's a Shinobi who defeated...
五影の１人
風影かぜかげを倒したほどの忍だ
the Kazekage,
one of the five great Kage.
Naruto probably wouldn't be
a match for him alone.
恐らく ナルト１人では
太刀打ちできない
先生は サクラちゃんのほうへ
行ってくれ
You go to Sakura, Sensei.
（カカシ）なっ…
フッ！
たっ…
I'll save...Gaara!
この！
俺が助ける！
フッ へヘッ
くあ～
（デイダラ）ふっ！
喝かつ！
（デイダラ）
この程度でやられてもらっちゃあ
It wouldn't be worthwhile if
you were beaten that easily.
やりがいがないからな
I won't let you...
have Gaara, no matter what!
この！
絶対ぜってえ 渡さねえ
（サソリ）見切っているか
They're seeing through it...huh?
If so...
ならば…
死ね！
Die!
（サソリ）
今の攻撃を避けきっただと
They completely dodged
my attack just now?
チヨバアはともかく 小娘まで
I understand Grandma Chiyo
being able to.
But that little girl...
なぜ？
How?!
チヨバアの動きは… なしか
Grandma Chiyo's...
not moving...?
I'm being mocked...
なめられたもんだ
I can't believe she's charging at me
head on without any backup...
援護もなしに
正面から突っ込んでくるとは
（サクラ）フッ！
（サソリ）ん？
It won't move!
動かねえ
そうかあ ババア！
I get it! Grandma...!
（チヨ）今じゃ サクラ！
Now, Sakura!
Smash him!
たたき込め！
はい！
Right!
I'm taking back Gaara!
我愛羅は 俺が取り戻す！
（デイダラ）
変わった人柱力じんちゅうりきだな お前
人柱力は“根暗で人嫌い”だと
聞いたがな うん
たあ…
（デイダラ）
こいつを除き 今までに２匹
人柱力を俺の仲間が倒したんだがな
そいつらの仲間も 里の者も
誰１人として 助けようとするヤツは
いなかったらしいぜ うん
それどころか むしろ
喜んでくれるヤツがいたそうだ
フッハハ
かわいそうな嫌われ者どうし
放っとけなかったか？ うん？
我愛羅は…
我愛羅は１尾を抜いたら死んだ
（デイダラ）
お前もじきに そうなるんだよ
こら！
あっ ハッ…
くっ…
てめえらは 許さねえ！
ハア ハア…
あっ はっ…
（チヨ）フン ようやく出てきたか
あれが本体？
（チヨ）はるばる孫の顔を見に
ここまでやって来たんじゃ
ハア ハア…
20年ぶりに…
まみえようではないか
♪～
～♪
さあ 残すところ あと１問
世界なんでも職業当てクイズ
最後の方は この方です
…って こいつ
頭っからマントかぶってんじゃねえか
（早押しボタンの音）
分かった！
有名な役者ね
（早押しボタンの音）
じゃあ
筋肉ムキムキの大工さん
制服のある仕事とか？
ヒントは？
ノーヒントです
分かるかあ！
残り時間わずか
わあ…
（終了の合図）
残念でした
それでは マントを
とっていただきましょう
次回
「サソリの素顔」
（ナルト）さあ ばあちゃん
ここが 木こノ葉はでも有名な
だんご屋だ
超甘党のアンコ先生 御用達の店だから
味は保証付きだぜ
（チヨ）ふ～ん
そうたいそうなものとも
思えんがのう
ばあちゃん ここは
ただのだんご屋じゃねえんだぜ
うちはイタチと干柿ほしがき鬼鮫きさめが
木ノ葉にやって来たとき
わざわざ 立ち寄った店なんだぜ
ほお あの暁あかつきの
まっ 冥土の土産に
１つ食ってみるかの
（ナルト）だはっ 冥土って
まだピンピンしてんじゃねえか
ぐふっ
（ナルト）なっ！
ば… ばあちゃん 大丈夫か？
おい！ ばあちゃんってば
（チヨ）ガクッ
な～に た… 大変だ！
おばちゃん
医療班 呼んでくれってばよ
（チヨ）ククク…
（ナルト）あっ？
な～んてな 死んだふり～
げへっ げへっ…
（ナルト）勘弁してくれってばよ
二ヒッ